MASAKI KOBAYASHI

https://www.makky.io makky@klis.tsukuba.ac.jp Tsukuba, Japan. Last Update: January 31, 2019

INTEREST

I am a 1st-year doctoral student at the Graduate School of Library, Information and Media Studies, University of Tsukuba. My current research interest is Human-Machine collaboration in Crowdsourcing for efficient microtask processing. Currently, I am studying to propose task assignment algorithms for Human and AI workers satisfying the data quality requirement from requesters.

I am also interested in developing web applications and, I am fluent in JavaScript, TypeScript, Ruby, and Python. I have experienced as a part-time engineer and an intern in more than ten companies. At present, I am working on the projects of ChainerUI and Crowd4U.

EDUCATION

University of Tsukuba, Japan.

April 2019 - Present

Ph.D Student,

Graduate School of Library, Information and Media Studies.

Advisors: Atsuyuki Morishima, Kei Wakabayashi and Hiromi Morita.

University of Tsukuba, Japan.

April 2017 - March 2019

Master of Informatics,

Graduate School of Library, Information and Media Studies.

Advisors: Atsuyuki Morishima and Hiromi Morita.

University of Tsukuba, Japan.

April 2013 - March 2017

Bachelor of Library and Information Science,

College of Knowledge and Library Sciences, School of Informatics.

Advisor: Atsuyuki Morishima.

PUBLICATIONS (FIRST AUTHOR)

INTERNATIONAL CONFERENCES (REFEREED)

Masaki Kobayashi, Hiromi Morita, Masaki Matsubara, Nobuyuki Shimizu and Atsuyuki Morishima. An Empirical Study on Short- and Long-term Effects of Self-Correction in Crowdsourced Microtasks. Proc. of the sixth AAAI Conference on Human Computation and Crowdsourcing(HCOMP), Zurich, 2018.7.

INTERNATIONAL WORKSHOPS, AND POSTERS

2. Masaki Kobayashi, Kei Wakabayashi, Atsuyuki Morishima. Quality-aware Dynamic Task Assignment in Human+AI Crowd. To appear in the poster track of TheWebConf 2020, Taipei.

DOMESTIC CONFERENCES (REFEREED)

3. Masaki Kobayashi, Kei Wakabayashi, Atsuyuki Morishima. Efficient microtask assignment to Human + AI Crowd. WebDB Forum 2019, Japan.

DOMESTIC CONFERENCES & WORKSHOPS (NOT REFEREED)

4. Masaki Kobayashi, Hiromi Morita, Masaki Matsubara, Nobuyuki Shimizu and Atsuyuki Morishima. Analysis of the effect of reference answer presentation on quality improvement of crowd workers. Forum on Data Engineering and Information Management (DEIM) 2019, Japan.

- 5. Masaki Kobayashi, Hiromi Morita, Masaki Matsubara, Nobuyuki Shimizu and Atsuyuki Morishima. Short-term and long-term effects of presenting reference answers from others in improving the quality of crowd workers. DEIM 2018, Japan.
- 6. Masaki Kobayashi, Nobuyuki Shimizu and Atsuyuki Morishima. A Self-Correcting Microtask Assignment Method Considering Workers Improvement. DEIM 2017, Japan.
- 7. Masaki Kobayashi, Takayasu Fushimi, Tetsuji Sato. Estimation of User Behavior Model Using Purchasing History. DEIM 2016, Japan.
- 8. Masaki Kobayashi, Takayasu Fushimi, Tetsuji Sato. An Input Support Method Based on Frequent Patterns of Cooking Recipes. In Proceedings of IEICE technical report, 2015, Japan.

WORK EXPERIENCE

Research Assistant University of Tsukuba, Japan.

April 2019 - Present

As a Member of the JST CREST CyborgCrowd Project. It is a Japanese funded research project to integrate crowdsourcing and AI technologies.

Engineer (Part-time) Preferred Networks, Inc.

October 2017 - Present

As a Member of the Chainer UI Team. I developed Chainer UI. It is a visualization and management tool for Chainer.

Engineer (Part-time) Bit Journey, Inc.

October 2017 - Present

Teaching Assistant University of Tsukuba, Japan.

April 2018 - December 2019

Database Technology Class and Introduction to Data Engineering Class

Intern Arm Treasure Data inc.

August 2018 - September 2018

Intern Preferred Networks, Inc.

August 2017 - September 2017

Engineer (Part-time) LINE Corporation.

April 2016

Intern CyberAgent inc.

September 2015

Intern National Institute of Informatics, Japan.

August 2015

Intern pixiv inc.

March 2015

Engineer (Part-time) 3-shake inc.

July2016 August 2017

Engineer (Part-time) BearTail inc.

May 2014 - March 2015

Engineer (Part-time) Has-key, inc.

August 2013 - March 2017

RESEARCH GRANTS

AIP Challenge Program JST AIP Network Lab, Japan. 1,000,000 JPY

August 2019 - March 2020

AWARDS

- Enterprise Award in WebDB Forum 2019 (LIFULL award and FRONTEO award), Japan.
- Repayment Exemption for Students with Excellent Grades, JASSO Type 1 scholarship, 1,200,000 JPY, 2019.
- Provosts Award, Graduate School of Library, Information and Media Studies, University of Tsukuba, Japan, 2019.
- Student Presentation Award in Forum on Data Engineering and Information Management (DEIM) 2017, Japan.
- Platinum Award, ThinkQuest JAPAN 2013.
- Grand Prize in ICT Challenge+R 2012, Ritsumeikan University, Japan. Title: Book Retrieval System using Google Street View of Original Panorama Images